gasbuddy.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy - GasBuddy.com

Effective Date: October 3, 2018 

Your privacy is important to GasBuddy, LLC (“GasBuddy”, “we”, or “us”) and we are committed to protecting the privacy of your information. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, store, share and protect your information in connection with the GasBuddy website located at www.GasBuddy.com as well as other localized GasBuddy websites, including DenverGasPrices.com, ToledoGasPrices.com or MichiganGasPrices.com (the “Sites”), and the services and tools (including, but not limited to, mobile applications and other software applications) related to the Sites (collectively, the “Service”). 

### Acceptance of Privacy Policy

Please read the GasBuddy [Terms of Service](https://help.gasbuddy.com/hc/en-us/articles/115005755528-Terms-of-Service) carefully before you use our Service. This Privacy Policy is part of, and is governed by, the terms and conditions set forth in the GasBuddy Terms of Service. 

By creating a GasBuddy account, or by otherwise accessing, visiting or using the Service, you expressly consent to the GasBuddy Terms of Service, and the data practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not feel comfortable with any part of this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Service, please discontinue your access or use of the Service immediately. 

If you purchase or access the Service through a third party service that provides a gateway to the Service, such as iTunes or Google Play (a “ **Gateway Service** ”), you will have a separate, additional account relationship with that Gateway Service. We have no control over the collection of such information by a Gateway Service, and any such collection or use will be subject to Gateway Service’s applicable privacy policies. 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the amended terms on the Service at least ten (10) days before the effective date of the changes. If you do not agree to the new terms, you may terminate your account within the applicable ten (10) day period by contacting us at [gbsupport@gasbuddy.com](mailto:gbsupport@gasbuddy.com), and you will not be bound by the amended terms. Otherwise, the new terms will take effect after ten (10) days. 

### The Personal Information We Collect

Personal information is any information that directly and indirectly identifies an individual user or that could be used to contact or locate him or her including name, email, phone number and address. Aggregated or anonymized information does not constitute personal information. 

  1. Account Information. We may collect personal information that you provide to us in connection with your use of the Service when you register as a user of the Service, send e-mail messages, forms, or other information to us through the Service, or enter a drawing or giveaway offered through the Service. If you register for a GasBuddy account directly through the Service, you will be required to provide your email address and create a user nickname and password. You can use the Service without registering, however, you may not be able to use certain features of the Service, such as entering drawings or giveaways that are offered through the Service.
  2. Information You Provide to Us.
    * GasBuddy Account. You may also choose to provide additional information in connection with your GasBuddy account, including a profile picture, your birthday, your hobbies, your car make/model/year or VIN, your job, your education and some of your favorite things, such as your favorite movies, food and TV shows. Providing this additional information is optional and you are not required to provide this information in order to use the Service.
    * Pay with GasBuddy. Some of our products, such as Pay with GasBuddy, require additional information from you to function. To use our Pay with GasBuddy card you will need to provide us access to your checking account and driver’s license.
    * Drawings & Giveaways. If you enter a drawing or giveaway offered through the Service you will be required to provide your postal address, including the street address, city, state and zip code.
  3. Information You Share on the Service. Some portions of the Service allow you to submit comments, reviews, ratings and other content. This content may be displayed on the Service and may be viewable by other users of the Service. In addition, if you have created a user profile and uploaded a photograph of yourself in connection with your GasBuddy account, other users of the Service will be able to see your user profile information and your photograph when you submit content to the Service while logged in to your GasBuddy account.
  4. Geolocation Information. If you access the Service through a mobile device, we will automatically collect information about your geolocation, including your geolocation relative to and within third party merchant locations. We cannot offer you some of the features of the Service, such as the “Find Gas Near Me” feature, if we cannot collect your geolocation information. If you do not want us to collect your geolocation information you may change your preferences through the “Settings” feature of the GasBuddy mobile application. Please see GasBuddy’s Disclosure of Information to Third Parties section of this Policy to see how GasBuddy may share your location data.
  5. Device Information. In addition, we may collect information such as your mobile device ID, device type, and your use of features, functions, or notifications on the device, as well as signal strength relating to WiFi or Bluetooth functionality, temperature, battery level, and similar technical data. We may collect this information even if you are not logged in to the Service. If you access the Service through a computer, we will automatically collect information such as your browser type and version, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the Service, IP address and standard web log information.
  6. Driving Data. If you access the Service through a mobile device, and if your preferences are set to permit collection of the information, we will also automatically collect information about your driving habits, including, but not limited to, driving distance, speed, acceleration and braking habits (collectively, “ **Driving Data** ”). Such collection occurs even if you are not logged in to the Service. We will be unable to offer you some of the features of the Service, such as the “Drives” feature, if we cannot collect your Driving Data. If you do not want us to collect your Driving Data, you may change your preferences through the “Settings” feature of the GasBuddy mobile application. GasBuddy may share your Driving Data as described in the Sharing Your Information With Third Parties section below.
  7. Information Provided to Us by Social Networking Services You Use. By logging into the Service through a third party social networking service, such as Facebook or Twitter, you give us permission to access, store and use any information that you permit the applicable third party social networking service to share with us in accordance with the privacy settings that are applicable to your account with that social networking service. We encourage you to review, and if necessary, adjust, your privacy settings on the applicable social networking service before logging in to the Service through a social networking service. Information that we receive from third party social networking service is stored and used by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Information Collected By Cookies And Similar Technologies

In some cases, we may use cookies and similar technologies, such as pixel tags, that automatically collect information. Cookies are small files, typically of letters and numbers, downloaded onto your computer or mobile device when you visit certain websites. When you return to these websites, or visit other websites that use the same cookies, the websites recognize these cookies and your browsing device. A cookie cannot read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other websites. 

Pixel tags are very small images or small pieces of data embedded in images, also known as “web beacons” or “clear GIFs,” that can recognize cookies, the time and date a page is viewed, a description of the page where the pixel tag is placed, and similar information from your computer or device. 

We generally treat information collected by cookies and other tracking technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that IP addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we treat cookie information with identifiers as personal information. 

Information that may be collected by cookies when you use the Service may include, without limitation: 

  * the pages you visit within the Service; 
  * the date and time of your visit to the Service; 
  * the amount of time you spend using the Service; 
  * the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; and/or 
  * your computer and connection information such as your browser type and version, operating system and platform.

Some of the functions performed by cookies are strictly necessary for us to be able to offer you our Service, while other cookies provide us with valuable insight about how we can improve our Service or help us with marketing our products and services to you based on your interests and preferences. 

The length of time a cookie will stay on your browsing device depends on whether it is a "persistent" or "session" cookie. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your browsing device until they expire or are deleted (i.e. after you have finished browsing). 

#### First and Third Party Cookies

When you access our Services, we or companies we work with may place cookies on your computer or other device. These technologies help us better understand user behavior, and inform us about which parts of our websites people have visited. 

We use both first-party and third-party cookies on our Service. First-party cookies are cookies that are placed on your device by us, while third-party cookies are set by parties other than GasBuddy. Third-party cookies are operated by third parties that can recognize your device both when it visits our Service and when it visits other websites or mobile apps. GasBuddy does not control how third-party cookies are used, and we encourage you to check the websites of any third-party cookie providers for more information about how they use cookie information. 

#### Advertising Tracking Technology and Analytics

GasBuddy uses third party service providers to display advertising on our Services and serve advertising on other third party sites that are more relevant to you or your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement, as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They remember that you have visited a website and this information may be shared with other organizations, such as advertisers. This means that after you have used our Services, you may see some advertisements about our Services elsewhere on the Internet. The information collected through this process by the third party service providers does not enable us or them to identify your name, contact details or other personal information that directly identifies you unless you choose to provide these. Such advertising will only be delivered where permitted by applicable law. 

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. The cookies and other technologies used by Google may collect personal information, but GasBuddy does not use Google Analytics to gather information that personally identifies you. The information generated by Google Analytics will be transmitted to and stored by Google and will be subject to Google’s privacy policies. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. 

#### Managing Cookies, Similar Technologies and Targeted Online Advertising.

  * Our Cookies ("First-Party Cookies"). You can use the browser with which you are viewing this website to enable, disable or delete cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the "Help", "Tools" or "Edit" settings). Please note, if you set your browser to disable cookies, you may not be able to access secure areas of the Site. Also, if you disable cookies other parts of the Services may not work properly. You can find more information about how to change your browser cookie settings at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
  * Third-Party Cookies. To opt-out of third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use targeting/advertising cookies, go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. Once you click the link, you may choose to opt-out of such advertising from all participating advertising companies or only advertising provided by specific advertising entities. For more information about third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use these technologies, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>.
  * Mobile Advertising. You can opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of advertising by accessing the settings in mobile device and following the instructions. If you opt-out, we will remove all data about you and will not collect any further data. The random ID previously assigned to you will be removed. Thus, if at a later stage, you decide to opt-in, we will be unable to continue and track you using the prior ID and you will for all practical purposes be a new user.
  * Do Not Track. Some Internet browsers - like Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari - include the ability to transmit "Do Not Track" or "DNT" signals. Since uniform standards for DNT signals have not been adopted, our Sites do not currently process or respond to DNT signals.
  * Flash Cookies. If you do not want Flash Cookies stored on your computer, you can adjust the settings of your Flash player to block Flash Cookies storage using the tools contained in the website storage settings panel. You can also control Flash Cookies by going to the global storage settings panel and following the instructions. Setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash Cookies may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications, including, potentially, Flash applications used in connection with our services or online content.

### How Your Personal Information Is Used

GasBuddy may use information that we collect about you through the Service: 

  * To provide access to the Service and to provide you with requested services and customer support and to process and respond to your inquiries; 
  * To personalize, customize, measure, and improve our services, content, and advertising and otherwise to enhance your experience of the Service; 
  * To prevent, detect, and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce the GasBuddy Terms of Service; 
  * To analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, usability, or popularity of the Service; 
  * To generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns; 
  * To compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes; 
  * To resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems; 
  * To contact you with information, including promotional, marketing and advertising information and recommendations that we believe may be of interest to you; 
  * To provide you with other services requested by you as described when we collect the information; 
  * To provide you with information we deem relevant when you visit third party merchant locations;
  * To send push notifications to your mobile device to provide updates about the Service and other relevant messages, to the extent you consent to this during registration process; and 
  * As otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy or the GasBuddy Terms of Service.

### Sharing of Information with Third Parties

We take care to allow your personal information to be accessed only by those who really need to in order to perform their tasks and duties, and to share with third parties who have a legitimate purpose for accessing it. We want you to understand when and with whom we may share the information we collect. We may share information that we collect through the Services with third parties as follows: 

  1. Our Service Providers. We may share your personal information with third party contractors or service providers who provide certain services to us or on our behalf, such as operating and supporting the Service or otherwise responding to your customer service requests. These service providers will only have access to the information needed to perform these limited functions on our behalf and are required to provide your information with at least the same level of protection and security as we use for the Service. 
  2. Our Business Customers. GasBuddy’s B2B Software-as-a-Service ( **SaaS** ), (collectively, the “ **Enterprise Services** ”), is designed to provide gas retailers a platform to maintain their station information, manage their brand, promote to their target consumer audience and measure success of their ads. By using our Enterprise Services, business customers can get access to your location information, ratings, reviews and in-app behavioral information. 
  3. Business Transfers or Bankruptcy. If GasBuddy becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, GasBuddy may share or transfer your personal information to a third party or parties in connection with the applicable transaction.
  4. Our Affiliates. We may share some or all of your personal information with our parent company, subsidiaries and corporate affiliates, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us for internal business purposes. We will require these entities to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy with regard to their use of your information.
  5. Law Enforcement Authorities. To the extent permitted or required by law, we may share your personal information with law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other GasBuddy user to legal liability, or to protect our rights or property, or during emergencies when safety is at risk.
  6. Third Party Business Partners. We share with third-party business partners the following information about you: 
    * _Mobile Data:_ If you access the Service through a mobile device, we may share your device ID and geolocation information with a few carefully selected third-party business partners that may use this information on behalf of themselves or their third party business partners to provide you with marketing information about products or services that may be of interest to you, for purposes related to advertising, analytics, attribution (e.g., measuring ad performance) and research.
    * _Driving Data:_ GasBuddy may provide your Driving Data to third party business partners in an anonymous form via an identifier so that these third party business partners can provide you with targeted offerings related to automobile insurance without knowing your identity. If you click on an insurance provider ad, that third party does not know your identity unless you contact the third party seeking to purchase their services.
    * _Location Data:_ We may share with Cuebiq Inc. (“ **Cuebiq** ”) your precise location information for purposes related to advertising, attribution (e.g., measuring ad performance), analytics and research to drive innovation to improve quality of life in underserved communities, in relation to natural disaster response, and for smart city development. You can opt-out of having your geo-location data shared with Cuebiq through the “Settings” feature of the GasBuddy mobile application or through the settings on your mobile device. For more information about how Cuebiq uses your geo-location information, you can visit: [Cuebiq's Privacy Policy](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.cuebiq.com_privacypolicy_&d=DwMGaQ&c=2s2mvbfY0UoSKkl6_Ol9wg&r=dsd5473ug_XC5keT52sCTBp_xSMViJtpLDQ-MI_dtRA&m=9t53kPXFYEAWuCBc6_onCwwBtj6r0EZ7hcVB5h3gL50&s=qbzT25YsFaP7n7HrSfC3k1tJ7P9NF9M8LfHJs8SkFzQ&e=).

### Collection of Information by Third Parties

If you visit the Service from a third-party website the third-party website may give you a unique code, cookie or graphic which will uniquely identify you. This will only happen if you link directly from a third party website to the Service. Your activities on the Service while this type of code is active may be reported back to the third party website. The presence of a third party navigation bar at the top of a webpage is an indication that the third party website may be able to see your activity on the Service. 

We may also provide social media features through the Service that enable you to share information with your social networks and to interact with the Service on various social media sites. Your use of these features may result in the collection or sharing of information about you by these sites, depending on the feature. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and settings on the social media sites with which you interact to make sure you understand the information that may be collected, used, and shared by those sites. 

### Information You Provide About Other Users

The “Tell a Friend” feature on the Sites allows you to send email notifications to your friends inviting them to use the Service. To use the “Tell a Friend” feature you will need to provide your friend’s name and email address. If you provide this information we will automatically send your friend an email asking them to visit the Sites. 

### Data Security

GasBuddy takes reasonable measures to protect the information you provide to GasBuddy or submit through the Service against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification. However, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to GasBuddy or submit through the Service and you do so at your own risk. No internet or email transmission is ever fully secure or error-free. Email sent to or through the Service may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information online and take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email. 

### Accessing, Changing and Managing Your Information

You may change and update the information you provide through the Service, or change your preferences concerning how we use your personal information, as follows: 

  1. Changing, Updating or Deleting Your Information. You may make changes to the user information you provided in connection with your GasBuddy account by logging in to your account and changing the applicable information. If you choose to terminate your account, you may also request that we delete your information by contacting us at [contact@gasbuddy.com](mailto:contact@gasbuddy.com). Following receipt of a request from you, we will take reasonable steps to update, correct or delete your information as required under the applicable law. 

In addition, if you are a California resident under the age of 18 and are a registered user of the Service, you may request that we remove content or information about you that you posted on the Service by (i) submitting a request in writing to [contact@gasbuddy.com](mailto:contact@gasbuddy.com) and (ii) clearly identifying the content or information you wish to have removed and providing sufficient information to allow us to locate the content or information to be removed. Please note, we are not required to, and may not be able to, erase or otherwise eliminate content or information if (a) other state or federal laws require us or a third party to maintain the content or information; (b) the content or information was posted, stored, or republished by another user; (c) the content or information is anonymized so that you cannot be individually identified; (d) you do not follow the instructions posted in this Privacy Policy on how to request removal of your content or information; or (e) you have received compensation or other consideration for providing the content. Further, nothing in this provision shall be construed to limit the authority of a law enforcement agency to obtain the applicable content or information. 

  2. Gateway Services (Third Parties). GasBuddy does not control the information you provide to Gateway Services. If you want to change your preferences with regard to how an applicable Gateway Service collects or uses your personal information in connection with the Service, you should review the privacy practices of the applicable Gateway Service and adjust your privacy or other settings directly through the applicable Gateway Service.

### Children's Privacy

GasBuddy is not intended for use by children under the age of thirteen (13). We will never knowingly collect personal information directly from children under the age of thirteen (13) without verifiable parental consent. If you are under the age of thirteen (13), please do not provide us with information of any kind whatsoever. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time with their children online and to be familiar with the websites they visit. If you have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received information from a child under the age of thirteen (13), please contact us immediately at [contact@gasbuddy.com](mailto:contact@gasbuddy.com). 

### International Users

The Services are offered in the United States, Canada and Australia only and are intended solely for residents of those jurisdictions. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Service or provide your information to us, your information will be transferred, processed and stored in the United States. U.S. privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Your agreement to our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of information in connection with the Service represents your agreement to this practice. If you do not want your personal information transferred to or processed or stored in the United States, you should not use the Service. 

### Retention of Your Information

We retain information for active GasBuddy accounts as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we may retain information from closed accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce the GasBuddy Terms of Service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain about you will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident you may request a notice from us describing what categories of personal information (if any) we have shared with third parties, including our corporate affiliates, for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. You may request such notice once a year and free of charge. To request a notice, please contact us as provided in the “Contact Us” section of this Policy and indicate in the email subject line “California Shine The Light Request” so that we can process your request. Please include your mailing address, state of residence and email address with your request. 

### How to Contact Us.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our use of the information we collect from you in connection with the Service, you may contact us by email at [contact@gasbuddy.com](mailto:contact@gasbuddy.com), or by postal mail at 99 Chauncy Street, 4th Floor, Boston, MA 02111 Attn: GasBuddy Customer Service.
